1805年4月  拿破仑在欧洲所向无敌
只有英国舰队能阻止他
汪洋大海成为生死战场
怒海争锋: 极地远征
"惊奇号"
28管大炮  197名船员
巴西北海岸
海军部命令欧杰克舰长
拦截法国私掠船 "地狱号"
它想要航向太平洋掀起大战
击沉  烧毁或抢夺它
没事了
Come on. It's all right.
Yes, it's all right.
威尔  醒醒
Wake up, Will.
右舷有动静
Starboard bow ahoy.
-什么东西?  斯莱德  -我好像听到声音
-What is it, Slade? -Thought I heard somethin'.
好像是铃声
Sounded like a bell.
-也许是渔船  -或是警示浮筒
-Native fishermen, perhaps. -Or a reef marker, sir.
科勒米  测量水深
Mr Calamy, the lead, if you please.
-水深五英寻  -五英寻
-By the mark, five fathom. -Five fathom.
只有沙子和贝壳
Sand and broken shell.
怎么了?
What is it?
右舷22度半浓雾中有东西
Two points off the starboard bow, in the fog bank.
什么东西?  船帆吗?
What was it? A sail?
-我不知道  -该击鼓备战吗?
-I don't know what it was. -Should we beat to quarters?
-我不确定  -你可是值星官
-I can't be certain. -You're officer of the watch.
哈伦  你要做决定
Hollom, you must make a decision.
击鼓备战
We shall beat to quarters.
起来  快起来
Rouse up. Sleepers awake.
动作快点
Move. Move along.
快点  快呀
Jump to it, boys. Jump to it.
向那边  快去
Light along there.
浓雾中有动静
Sighting in heavy fog.
-爬上船桅  -把小艇放下去
-Handsomely on the yards tackle. -Topmen aloft.
在哪里?
Where away?
右舷22度半不到一英里
Two points off the starboard bow, sir. Not a mile distant.
-你确定吗?  -确定
-You sure, Mr Hollom? -Yes, sir.
是军舰吗?
Man-of-war?
我不知道
I don't know, sir.
它一闪而过  我只看到影子
It was only for a moment. I thought I saw a shape.
-你有看到吗?  科勒米  -没有
-Did you see it, Mr Calamy? -No, sir.
你做得对  回到岗位去
You did the right thing, Mr Hollom. Go to your stations.
汤姆  你来指挥
The deck's yours, Tom.
是
Sir.
把小艇放下去  用力拉紧
Clear away. And launch boats.
-把它搬下去回到岗位  -你们听到了
-Quit your dawdling. -You heard the man.
放下去
Lower away.
大家用力拉
Haul both your yard tackles.
敲钟
Strike the bell.
趴下  快趴下
Down. All hands down.
全体备战  霍拉  损坏报告
Hands to your stations. Mr Hollar, damage report, if you please.
18磅重炮弹造成  我要逼近它用右舷大炮迎敌
18-pounders. We'll have to get closer. Run out the starboard battery.
艾伦  迎风转向  逼近敌舰旁边
Mr Allen, come up on the wind. Lay me alongside at pistol-shot.
狙击手爬到制高点  霍华德
Sharpshooters to the tops, Mr Howard.
带你的手下爬上主桅
Sergeant. Take your section into the main top.
抬头挺胸英勇抗敌
We stand tall on the quarterdeck. All of us.
-波义耳  升旗  -是  船长
-Mr Boyle, run up the colors. -Aye, sir.
记在船长日志上  "第六声钟响时迎敌"
Note for the log, Mr Watt. "Engaged enemy frigate at six bells."
誓死奋战
-笔直地冲过去  -冲过去
-Straight at 'em, Mr Mowett. -Straight at 'em, sir.
比尔
Bill.
别拿剑  下去
Leave the swords. Get the captain's silver below.
还没进入射程  等到接近了再开炮
She's not in range yet. Stand fast till she's close enough.
-再靠近一点  -遵命
-Close with him amidships. -Midships it is, sir.
千万别弄掉了
For God's sake, don't drop anything.
稳住
Steady.
-坚守岗位  -坚守岗位  勇敢一点
-Hold your positions. -Hold your position. Courage, now.
-稳住了稳住了  -我们会让他们好看
-Hold steady, boys. -Don't worry, lads, we'll serve 'em out yet.
你受伤了长官  戴维斯  杰米  把他带下去
Mr Pullings, sir. Davies, Jemmy, get Mr Pullings below.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
布雷克尼  通知船长
Mr Blakeney, pass the word for the captain.
赶快清理
Clear the forward pin rails.
沙子多洒一点
More sand on the floor.
乘着浪头  开炮
On the up-roll, fire!
趴下
Down!
保护舵柄  来人  把伤者抬下去
Relieving-tackles on the tiller. You men, collect these wounded.
-继续开炮  -重新装弹药
-Keep 'em spitting, Mr Calamy. -Aye, sir. Reload and give 'em hell.
"地狱号"
船长  快到船尾
Sir. To the taffrail.
方向舵损坏  无法掌舵
The rudder's shot away. The steering don't answer.
我们成了瓮中之鳖
We're fish in a barrel.
怎么不开炮?
Why are we not firing?
让我过去
Let me through.
这儿  乔
Here, Joe.
快塞住
Hold it in there.
-他在左船首  -拿出手枪
-He's on the larboard bow, sir. -Bring up your small arms.
准备抗敌登船
Prepare to repel boarders.
拿了枪  等船长下令
Seize your weapons and wait for the word.
请下令
Your orders, sir?
叫炮兵到甲板船尾绑绳索  下去划小艇
Call the gun crews to deck. Rig man-ropes over the stern and pull the boats in.
把船拖进浓雾
Put us in that fog, Tom.
用力划拼命划  大家一起划
Pull together, men.
划进浓雾
Pull for the fog bank.
大炮搬过来
Run 'em out.
开炮
Fire!
船身破裂  快塞住缺口
She's opened up a seam. We need to get some oakum and pound it in.
拿槌子和铁条
Joe, a mallet and some irons.
它追上来了
She's gaining on us.
-我们快要摆脱了  -快划呀
-We're nearly there, boys. -Pull.
-用力划呀  -进了那团雾就好了
-Reach for it, men. -We're home inside that fog.
开炮
Fire!
为杰克船长用力划
Pull for Lucky Jack.
成功了
We've done it.
不要出声
Pipe down. Silence on deck.
他们不会找到我们
They'll not find us in here.
安静  不准大喊大叫
Quiet, lads. No shouts, no calls.
不要划了
Avast rowing.
干得好  各位
Well done, lads.
水只淹到两英尺六英寸  就停了
Two feet six inches, sir, and holding.
-干得好  拉姆  -谢谢
-Good work, Mr Lamb. -Thank you, sir.
有多少人伤亡?
So, what's the butcher's bill?
9人阵亡  27人受伤
Nine dead, 27 wounded.
乔・普雷斯
Joe Plaice.
他的头骨破裂  很严重
He has a severely depressed fracture of the skull.
恐怕撑不过今晚
I don't think he'll see out the night.
布雷克尼勋爵
Lord Blakeney.
我只是断了只手臂
Just a broken arm, sir.
你不用担心
You're in very good hands.
你跟他父亲是好朋友  我会尽力而为
I'm doing everything I can. I know you were close to his father.
他父亲一定会谅解  他的母亲就...
His father would've understood. He knew the life. His mother, however...
我看看你的伤口
Let me take a look at that brow of yours.
什么?
What?
他很厉害  突然冒出来进行偷袭
Damn, he was good. Just came out of nowhere.
先开炮来个下马威  然后攻击船尾把方向舵打断
Hit us with a full broadside, cut across our tail and took out our rudder.
对方的炮兵神准
Damn fine gunnery.
起浓雾我们才能脱身  运气真好
We only slipped away because of the fog. Quite fortunate, really.
他有上风优势  我有老天保佑
He may have had the weather gauge, but we had the weather gods.
我不太明白你在说什么
I have no idea what it is you're talking about,
不过他是蛮厉害的
but he did seem to come off rather well.
我们航行了七个礼拜  他却知道在哪里偷袭我们
Seven weeks sailing, and he happens in darkness on our exact position.
法军在英国和各地都有间谍  我们也一样
The French have their spies in England and elsewhere. As do we.
没错
Indeed.
他若知道我们在找他  就该闪避
If he knew we were looking for him, he could have stood to sea and passed well clear.
也许他也在找我们
Well then, perhaps he was looking for us.
暗礁
暗沙
它不是护卫舰才有鬼
If she was a frigate, then I am a Dutchman.
敌强我弱  输了并不丢脸
It was an unfair match. There was no dishonor in it.
它是艘二重甲板船
She was more like a ship of the line.
你会不禁对它的船身感到惊讶
You have to wonder about her hull. Our shots wouldn't penetrate.
从两百码外开炮都伤不了它
Triple-shotted at 200 yards -no effect.
它有上风优势和猛烈的炮火优势
She had the weather gauge and a clear advantage in firepower.
什么是上风优势?
What is the weather gauge?
-你要我画给你看吗?  -别在桌布上乱画
-Shall I show you again, Stephen? -Not on the cloth.
它的位置在上风处  所以能左右战局
It means she had the wind in her favor, therefore control of the engagement.
它的大炮也射得比我们远
And she had longer guns, so she could hit us beyond our range.
承认吧  我们一败涂地
The simple fact is we were soundly beaten.
-拿破仑在太平洋部署重型护卫舰  -这样一来他就稳操胜算
-Heavy frigate like that in the Pacific... -Could tip the war in Napoleon's favor.
跟这艘军舰比起来  "惊奇号" 太老了
By comparison, the Surprise is a somewhat aged man-of-war.
-我说错了吗?  -你说我老了吗?
-Am I not correct? -Would you call me an aged man of war?
"惊奇号" 并不老  一点都不老
The Surprise is not old. No one would call her old.
它的船首方正船身线条优美  船坚炮利  迅速敏捷
She has a bluff bow, lovely lines. She's a fine sea boat, weatherly, stiff and fast.
看是谁操纵了  可以非常快
Very fast, if she's well-handled.
它一点都不老
No, she's not old.
它正值黄金年华
She's in her prime.
主桅和后帆需要修复  前桅帆破裂  要用备用帆
We can patch up the main and mizzen. Foresail's gone, so we'll bend our spare.
拉姆认为只要稍作修补  我们就能安全返航
Mr Lamb is confident with basic repairs. We can get home as we are.
我们还不回去
We're not going home.
修船一定要靠岸  "地狱号" 可能还在找我们
But to refit we need a port, and the Acheron may be still looking for us.
我们可以在海上修船  这儿有暗沙的浅水海域
We can refit at sea. Here, where it shoals.
地狱号要到南太平洋开战  我们必须阻止它
As you said, she is taking the war to the South Seas. We are supposed to stop her.
但是请恕我直言  它的实力比我们强太多了
But, sir...with respect...she's a vastly heavier ship. She's out of our class.
等我们修好船它都到合恩角了
She could be halfway to Cape Horn by the time we're repaired.
那就更不能浪费时间
Well then, there's not a moment to lose.
最后一针是穿过鼻孔吗?
Is it true they put the last stitch through your nose?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
乔说  你死后
Joe said when you die,
他们会在你鼻孔上面缝一针
they stitch you in your hammock with the last stitch in your nose,
确定你不是在睡觉
just to make sure you're not asleep.
别缝我的鼻孔好不好?
Not through the nose. You'll tell them?
没关系鸦片酊能止痛
It's all right. It's just the laudanum speaking.
你是最勇敢的病人
I've never seen a braver patient.
放心  我很快会把你修好
Poor darling. Never mind, soon have you fixed up.
快去工作
I want good work now.
两个人去修补前桅板  罗伯茨  查德威克
I'll need two men into the starboard forechannels. Roberts, Chadwick.
做得很好
That's nice work there.
这修不好的  这些给我更换掉
Repair won't do here. I need these replaced.
科勒米  你一定有兴趣
Mr Calamy. There's something might interest you here.
你看  这是船长当见习官时刻的
Look. The captain carved that. When he was a mid, no more than your age.
他从小就待在这艘船上
He's known this ship man and boy.
这艘船上流了太多他的血
He says there's enough of his blood in the woodwork
几乎算是他的亲人
for the ship to almost be a relation.
我同意你的说法  你真是知识渊博
I do understand your point. Your knowledge is beyond question.
但是如果现在才去找木材
However, a week in the Brazilian rain forest
一定来不及
looking for a new mast simply will not do.
"地狱号" 早就到中国了
The Acheron will be halfway to China.
拉姆会尽全力抢修船身  大家都要跟他一样
Mr Lamb, as always, will do his best. Which is all I can hope to expect from any man.
那是他的脑浆吗?
Is them his brains?
不这是血浆  这才是他的大脑
No, that's just dried blood. Those are his brains.
他可是妙手回春的医生
Physician, he is. Ain't one of your common surgeons.
把硬币给我
-Can I have the coin, please? -Sir.
他在陆地上不轻易替人看病
He wouldn't look at you for under ten guineas on land.
他也很了解鸟兽习性
And he knows his birds and beasts.
他连甲虫在想什么都知道
You show him a beetle and he'll tell you what it's thinking.
回去做事吧懒虫  吹哨子
Back to work, you loafers. Eckhart, use your pipe.
赶快回去做事
Let's get on with it, gentlemen.
别净在这儿打混
You're not a pennyweight of use gawpin' here.
他还是没开口
Still hasn't said a word, sir.
布雷克尼勋爵  好点吗?
Lord Blakeney. Feeling better?
好多了  谢谢
Much better, thank you, sir.
那就好
Well, good. Good.
医生说你很爱看书  所以我...
The doctor told me you were fond of reading, so I...
《纳尔逊将军的胜仗》
有他打的胜仗和很棒的插图
It has all of his major battles and some fine illustrations.
谢谢你  船长
Thank you, sir.
你见过纳尔逊将军吗?
Did you ever meet Lord Nelson, sir?
我为他打过尼罗河战役  伟大的胜仗
I had the honor of serving with him. At the Nile. A great victory.
这本书上有记载  如果我没记错是第135页
You can find it in here, actually. Page 135, if I'm not mistaken.
是的
Yes.
他是个什么样的人?
May I beg you to tell me what kind of man he is?
你只要看书就知道
You should read the book.
我会的  谢谢
I will, sir. Thank you.
他们又在拉了  叽叽嘎嘎
Here we go again. Scrape-scrape, screech-screech.
没有一首能跳舞  喝得烂醉了也不行
Never a tune you could dance to, not if you were drunk as Davy's sow.
这样如何?
How about this?
你想来首激昂的曲子吗?
Or are you in the mood for something more aggressive?
"挚爱的苏菲..."
敬礼
Salute.
脱帽
Hats off.
什么事?
What's all this about?
-这是什么?  -那艘鬼船
-What's this? -It's the phantom, sir.
大家都说 "地狱号" 是鬼船
Excuse me. That's what the men call it. It's the Acheron, sir.
他看到它的建造过程
You see, Will here, he seen her being built.
在波士顿  在战前  它是美国佬建造的
In Boston, sir. During the peace. But she's Yankee-built, sir.
他在那里结婚  他妻子的表弟在船坞工作
He was getting married, and his wife's second cousin works in the yards,
带他看过那艘船
so Will here saw the ship out of water.
我看到那艘船有点古怪  所以就请乔...
Sir, I saw there was something right strange about her, so I asked Joe...
我照他说的做了模型
So he described it to me and I knocked you up a model, sir.
-这个模型很准确?  -完全准确
-And this framing is accurate? -Exactly accurate, sir.
-谢谢两位  -谢谢
-Thank you, lads. -Thank you, sir.
多给他们一份朗姆酒
Killick, an extra ration of rum for these men.
谢谢船长
Thank you very much, sir.
-那是留着过节喝的  -过节喝葡萄酒
-Which I was saving for Salutin' Day. -We'll drink wine.
不可思议
Oh, drink wine on Salutin' Day.
上宽下窄的船首
Bluff above the water and sharp below.
流线形的船身  所以船速才会那么快
Gives the hull a finer entry and a long run as she goes aft. That's why she's so fast.
船身虽重  船速却很快
Heavier, but fast despite it.
这是未来的设计  我们生活的时代真是无比惊奇
That's the future. What a fascinating modern age we live in.
它的船壳至少有两英尺厚
Planking and framing like that would make her hull 2ft thick. Solid oak.
怪不得射不穿  船速最快大概能到12至14节
That's why we couldn't dent her. She's probably capable of making 12 to 14 knots.
多亏有瓦利跟他妻子的表弟
Now we know. Thank God for Warley and his wife's second cousin.
它一天能航行280英里
She could be doing up to 280 miles a day.
就算追得上它  想要击败它...
Even if we did catch up with her, I mean, to take her...
比登天还难  它有44管大炮
She's out of our class. She's a 44-gun ship.
它的罩门跟我们一样是船尾
She's still vulnerable at the stern, like the rest of us.
亲爱的  一个吻多少钱?
Hello, darling. How much for a kiss?
(葡萄牙语) 一个吻多少钱?
Quanto cost-o kiss-o?
-你的名字?  -我叫玛莉亚
-Name? -My name is Maria.
我要用斧头换箭  快点
Give us arrows. I give ax. Quick, mate.
谢谢
Thank you, mate.
借过一下
Gangway for the mail, please.
拿去  这是重要的邮件
Here we are. Very important mail. Letters.
他说什么?
What's he saying?
一艘法国战舰  10号在这里靠岸后往南航行
A large man-of-war, French, stopped here on the 10th, then headed south.
附近的某处
Somewhere here.
比我们快三星期
A full three weeks ahead.
可恶
Damn.
汤姆  赶快完成交易
All right, Tom, let's get all this squared away.
霍拉  尽快完成交易
Aye, sir. Mr Hollar. Let us complete our business here.
准备起锚
Hands, prepare to weigh anchor.
别光顾着泡妞
Put that woman down, Slade.
这是皇家海军  不是让你来逛窑子的
This is a ship of His Majesty's Navy, not a floating bordello.
大家动手  把补给品搬上去
All hands, get these provisions stowed.
很好
Well done.
各位
Gentlemen.
敬妻子和情人
To wives and to sweethearts.
愿她们永不相见
May they never meet.
霍华德  把酒瓶拿来
Mr Howard, the bottle. The bottle stands by you, sir.
船长?
Sir?
布雷克尼说  你为纳尔逊将军打过仗
Excuse me, sir, but Mr Blakeney said that you served under Lord Nelson at the Nile.
没错  当年我是个年轻的上尉  年纪跟你差不多
Indeed. I was a young lieutenant, not much older than you are now.
普灵只是个见习官
And Mr Pullings was a sniveling midshipman,
还一直吵着想回家
still yearning for hearth and home.
你见过他吗?  能谈谈他吗?
Did you meet him, sir? Can you tell me what he's like?
我很荣幸与他共餐两次
I have had the honor of dining with him twice.
他两次都有跟我说话
He spoke to me on both occasions.
他是个有远见的战略家
A master tactician and a man of singular vision.
他打仗时总是说  "别用什么战略  冲上去就打"
He always said in battle "Never mind the maneuvers, just go straight at 'em."
他也许没谋略  却有领导才能
Some would say not a great seaman, but a great leader.
英国要靠他对抗拿破仑
He's England's only hope if old Boney intends to invade.
请你说说他的趣事
Sir, might we press you for an anecdote?
他第一次跟我说的话
The first time that he spoke to me,
我永远也忘不了  好像是昨天一样
I shall never forget his words. I remember it like it was yesterday.
他从餐桌另一边看着我说:
He leaned across the table, he looked me straight in the eye,
"奥布里  请把盐瓶递给我"
and he said "Aubrey, may I trouble you for the salt?"
我一直试着模仿他的口气
I've always tried to say it exactly as he did ever since.
第二次他说了个故事
The second time, the second time he told me a story
有人在寒夜里请他穿大衣
about how someone offered him a boat cloak on a cold night.
他并没有穿  他说他很暖和
And he said no, he didn't need it. That he was quite warm.
他的爱国心让他全身暖呼呼
His zeal for king and country kept him warm.
听起来很做作  如果是别人
I know it sounds absurd, and were it from another man,
我一定瞧不起他  觉得他很假
you'd cry out "What pitiful stuff" and dismiss it as mere enthusiasm.
但出自纳尔逊的口
But with Nelson,
你知道那是真心话
you felt your heart glow.
-对吧普灵  -没错
-Wouldn't you say, Mr Pullings? -You did indeed, sir.
他是唯一没被权力腐化的人
Well then, he would seem to be the exception to the rule that authority corrupts.
敬纳尔逊将军
To Lord Nelson.
你看到这两只小虫吗?
Do you see those two weevils, Doctor?
看到了
I do.
你会选哪一只?
Which would you choose?
这两只其实一模一样  它们都是象鼻虫
Neither. There's no difference between them. They're the same species of curculio.
如果你非选不可呢?
If you had to choose.
必须要做出一个抉择的话...
If you were forced to make a choice. If there was no other...
如果你硬要我选
Well then, if you're going to push me,
我会选右边这只
I would choose the right-hand weevil.
它看起来比较凶恶
It has significant advantage in both length and breadth.
我赢了  你被我说倒了
There, I have you. You're completely dished.
你要知道  在军中有句话说  二恶相权取其轻
Do you not know that in the service one must always choose the lesser of two weevils?
这笑话太冷了
He who would pun would pick a pocket.
逊毙了
Really. Weevils.
二恶相权取其轻
To the lesser of two weevils.
乔
Yay, Joe.
乔  继续
Go on, Joe.
上帝可以收回我的灵魂
The Lord taketh,
也可以把它还给我
and the Lord giveth away.
听到吗?  他开口了耶
You hear that? He said something.
医生  他说话了
Doctor. He spoke, Doctor.
干得好  史蒂芬
Well done indeed, Stephen.
*Adieu to you Spanish ladies*
*Farewell and adieu to you ladies of Spain*
*For we've received orders to sail for old England*
*We hope in a short time to see you again*
哈伦的歌声真好听
What a wonderfully true voice Mr Hollom possesses.
是啊
Indeed.
*Come, all you bold young thoughtless men*
*A warning take by me*
*And never leave your happy homes to sail the raging sea*
海上有动静
On deck there. Sail ho.
好像是一艘船
Looks like a frigate.
它怎么来的?
How did it get there?
-我们一定要转过去迎敌  -但是它又有上风优势
-We must turn and fight. -But he has the weather gauge again.
它一定早就在等我们上钩
He must've been watching us from some inlet.
它吃定我们了  怎么办?
My God. What can we do? He has us by the hip.
逃得越快越好
Run like smoke and oakum.
-船帆不够用  -若有必要连手帕都要用上
-We'll have to bend every sail. -We'll put up our handkerchiefs if we have to.
我们一定要逃走  快去吧  艾伦
We must survive this day. Let's get about it. Mr Allen, gentlemen.
全体船员  扬帆
All hands, make sail.
这是他第二次占上风  不会有第三次
This is the second time he's done this to me. There will not be a third.
那是一艘恶魔开的鬼船
I tell ya, the devil's at the wheel of that there phantom ship.
你最好小心点
You better hold fast.
这家伙跟我有仇吗?
What is it with this man?
我是不是杀了他的亲人?  他的爱子?
Did I kill a relative of his in battle, perhaps? His boy, God forbid?
他的作风跟你很像  杰克
He fights like you, Jack.
把太阳调到海平线上
Bring the sun down to the horizon.
当它碰到海平线  威廉森  注意看
When its lower limb is touching the horizon... Williamson, look to your sextant.
当太阳不再动
When the orb is no longer rising,
它就达到了顶点  那就是正午
then it has reached its zenith and that would be noon.
-船长  -普灵
-Sir? -Mr Pullings.
-你会了吗?  -会了
-Do you make noon, Mr Hollom? -Yes, sir.
那就去教他们吧
Call noon. It's your class.
-正午了  -尼克斯  中午十二时
-Sir, that's noon. -Mr Nichols, make that twelve.
还有六小时?
Six hours?
最多五小时
Five at most.
天黑前别被它追上来
Just keep us out of her reach until nightfall.
它会跟我们一样  动作要快一点
She's to look like us, lads, don't forget. Jibbo, make fast those whips.
风势太大  主桅不能做太高
We didn't want to make it any taller, on account of this wind.
-他们在做什么?  -你的第一艘船
-Excuse me, sir, but what are they building? -Your first command.
快点  它要追上来了
Quickly. She'll be on top of us.
放下吊在船桅上的木筏
Take the weight on the yard tackles.
把木筏推出去
Fend her off.
放下去
Lower away on the main.
-我可不想失去你  -是  先生
-Wouldn't want to lose you. -Aye, sir.
那里有系索  把它拖到船尾
There's a painter. Pass her aft. Outside everything, mind.
快  它十分钟后就能追上来
Lively now. We've not ten minutes before he's up with us.
-记着船长教你的  -用力拉
-Mind what the captain told you. -Pull, boys. That's it.
现在
Now.
基里克  熄灯
Killick there. Douse your light.
艾伦  准备好
Mr Allen, make ready.
我们钓到一条大鱼
Hello. We caught a fish.
你来掌舵  波登
Take the helm, Bonden.
这很好玩吧
-Now, tell me that wasn't fun. -Yes, sir.
左满舵
Hard a'larboard.
叫大家下去休息  我来值星
Stand the men down, Mr Pullings. I'll take this watch.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
莫维  艾伦  别出声  快去吧
Mr Mowett, Mr Allen, calmly now. You know his orders.
干得好
Well done, sir.
它一定是艘鬼船  它突然就跟在后面
She's a right phantom, she is. The way she come up again, right behind us like that.
不晓得从哪儿冒出来  就像第一次在浓雾中出现
Out of nowhere. And right behind us. Like that first time, out the fog.
用大炮打它都没用
With our shot bouncin' off her.
难怪船长的绰号是幸运杰克
Captain's not called Lucky Jack for no reason.
不管怎样它还是艘私掠船  幸运杰克会打败它的
Phantom or no, she's a privateer, and Lucky Jack'll have her.
对付鬼船不能只靠运气
You need more than luck 'gainst a phantom.
-那是海盗船吗?  -他们不是海盗
-Is she like a pirate? -No, they're not pirates, Lofty.
如果是的话  我们就能把他们吊死
Oh, no. If they were, we could hang them when we catch 'em.
法国佬给私掠船的命令是
Privateer gets a piece of paper from the Frenchies
只要看到英国船就可以开炮
says they can hunt down anything with our flag.
他们也抢了不少商船
They go after rich merchantmen and the like.
逮到他们就能分不少钱
But think on our share of the prize money.
船上一定有很多黄金  龙涎香  还有用不完的金银珠宝
She'll be loaded with gold and ambergris and all the gems of Araby.
就算发了财也得活着回家
That's all very well, Nagle. Got to get home to spend it, but.
死人可不会请我喝酒
Never met a dead man who bought me a drink.
你也没请活人喝过酒
And I've never met a live one that you bought one for, neither.
你何必三更半夜挨寒受冻  最后一杯咖啡
Sitting up all night, catching your death of cold. That's the last of the coffee, too.
谢谢你
Thank you, Killick.
波登
Bonden.
不必向东了  设定航向  西南偏南
That's enough easting. Set a course sou'-sou'west.
遵命  西南偏南
Aye, sir. Sou'-sou'west.
前有船只
Sail.
右舷船首22度半
Two points off starboard bow.
幸运杰克万岁
Three cheers for Lucky Jack.
是我们的了
She's ours, boys.
你赢了
Foul. You got away before me.
升起高低前桅帆
-Set royals and courses. -Sir.
叫人站在栏杆边
Have the idlers placed along the rails.
他太神了
I've never seen the like.
绕一百海里后咬住敌舰船尾
It has to be more than 100 sea miles and he brings us up on his tail.
这才叫航海高手
That's seamanship, Mr Pullings. My God, that's seamanship.
我就说会成功  天黑就能追上去
Told you it would work, Will. We'll have them by nightfall.
-他们死定了  -风向对我们有利
-I think we've got him, sir. -And the wind favors us this time.
话别说的太早
Don't count your eggs before they're in the pudding.
不过只要能追上去  就能逮到他们
Still, if we can close this gap and get up behind her, she may well be ours.
老天保佑快刮强风
Touch wood. Scratch a stay.
转三圈  愿老天保佑我们
Turn three times. May the Lord and saints preserve us.
转过来
Turn.
动作快点  快把救生索绑好
Move along, man. We'll have lost him before you rig it up.
停
Hold.
-船速十二节  -十二节  很好
-12 knots, sir. -That's 12 knots. That's good.
再多点  派人站到上风面
I want more. Have all the spare hands placed on the windward rail.
霍拉  把大家都叫起来
Mr Hollar. Rouse up the off-watch.
全都站到右舷栏杆
All hands on starboard rail.
迎风扬起左顶帆
Come up the larboard topsail sheets.
-船帆全都升起  -超过极限  船帆就会被吹走
-We're crackin' on. -We'll be crackin' up if he don't watch it.
船长知道这艘船的极限
Captain knows this ship. He knows what she can take.
把前后救生索绑好
Mr Hollar, I want lifelines fore and aft.
别偷懒
No lounging, boy.
前后救生索把小艇绑牢
Lifelines, fore and aft. Double-grape that launch.
那是合恩角
Cape Horn, Doctor.
快盖起来  这儿的水够多了
Close the lid. There's enough water in the grog.
多谢了
Thank you for that, Davies.
船长还想追下去吗?
Reckon the captain will follow him round the Horn, every stitch of canvas flying?
就算追到地狱  他也要追上去
I reckon he'd follow him to the gates of hell.
那艘恶魔船要把我们带入陷阱
It's a devil ship, I tell ya. And it's leadin' us right into a trap.
它要带我们冲向合恩角
She's making a run for the Horn, sir.
我很怕船桅会被吹断
I'll not vouch for this mast. Not around the Horn.
我会把你的话记在日志
Thank you. Your comments will be noted in the log.
掌帆员站好岗位  风太大了  快收帆
Sail trimmers to their stations. Get the sails off her, lads. She's over-pressed.
用力拉下来
Give 'em a pull and belay.
就快追到了  我不会放弃
We're closing on her, Tom. I'll not give up now.
迎风转向  设定航向  西南偏西
Come up on the wind, Barret. Set a course sou'west by west.
遵命  西南偏西
Sou'west by west, sir.
科勒米
Mr Calamy.
西南偏西
Idlers and waisters below.
我们要去合恩角
We're for the Horn, boys.
把顶帆收起来
Close reef topsails.
快点  伙计们
Lively, lads.
封舱  别等沉船了就来不及了
Batten down those hatches before we're on the bottom.
约翰逊  图拉维  收起后帆
Johansson, Truelove. To the mizzen.
都绑紧了
All secure.
很好
Down ye go, lads.
帮瓦利把后桅顶帆拉下来
Mr Hollom, help young Warley on the mizzen topgallant.
-我需要更多人手  -快去
-I'll need more men, sir. -Yes. Go.
哈伦  帮帮我
Mr Hollom, sir. Help me.
快去帮忙
Tudor, Ellers. To Mr Allen.
爬上去把后桅顶帆收起来
You men, lay aloft. The mizzen topgallant. Light along.
救命啊
Help.
Help me.
有人落海
Man overboard.
后桅没有了  大伙到船艉
Mizzen's gone. Hands to the taffrail.
在那儿
He's over there, sir.
快游过去  快点
Swim for the wreckage, man. Swim.
我在这儿
Over here.
快把木桶等等能浮的东西都丢下海
Mr Allen, gratings and barrels, anything that floats, overboard.
船身在倾斜  就快翻船了
She's broaching. We're losing her.
残骸会把船身拖下去
Sir, the wreckage is acting as a sea anchor.
不砍断救生索就会沉船
We must cut it loose. It's going to sink us.
他就快游到了
Sir, he's going to make it. He can do it.
-加油  -快游呀
-Come on, Will. -Come on. Hand over hand.
快游呀  快游过去  就快沉船了
For God's sake, Will, swim. Swim for the wreckage, Will.
你行的
You can do it, Will.
-加油  -加油  威尔
-Swim. Come on. -Come on, Will. Swim.
1805年直布罗陀  瓦利
重返家园
-他又来了  -谁?
-He's been at it again. -Who's that, then?
-瘟神  -什么东西?
-The Jonah. -What's that?
打仗时  战死比较能令人接受
The deaths in actual battle are the easiest to bear.
死在我的手术刀下  或是因为感染而死的弟兄
For my own part, those who die under my knife, or from some subsequent infection,
我总是说他们是死在敌人手上  不是死在我手上
I have to remind myself that it was the enemy that killed them, not me.
他是战争的牺牲者
That young man was a casualty of war.
你也说二恶相权取其轻
As you said yourself, you have to choose the lesser of two evils.
小虫
Weevils.
瓦利人缘很好  船员都会很难过
The crew will take it badly. Warley was popular.
他们有向你反映什么吗?
Have they expressed any feelings on the matter to you?
我在回答之前要先问下
Jack, before answering, I'm compelled to ask,
我该把你当朋友还是船长?
am I speaking with my old friend or to the ship's captain?
我会跟船长说我最痛恨内奸
To the captain I'd say there's little I detest more than an informer.
-你活像个爱尔兰人  -我就是爱尔兰人
-Now you're talking like an Irishman. -I am an Irishman.
那就把我当朋友
As a friend, then.
身为你的朋友  我从没怀疑过你当船长的能力
As a friend, I would say that I have never once doubted your abilities as a captain.
有话就直说吧
Speak plainly, Stephen.
也许我们早就该返航
Perhaps we should have turned back weeks ago.
跟随幸运杰克的弟兄们
The men, of course they would follow Lucky Jack anywhere,
都很有自信能打胜仗
rightfully confident of victory.
这就是问题所在  你很少吃败仗
But therein lies the problem. You're not accustomed to defeat.
追逐这艘比我们更强的战舰
And chasing this larger, faster ship with its long guns
也许是你的自尊心在作祟
is beginning to smack of pride.
这不是自尊  这是我的职责
It's not a question of pride. It is a question of duty.
职责  你说的好伟大哦
Duty. Yes, I've heard it well spoken of.
尽管嘲笑我吧  反正你只会在鸡蛋里挑骨头
Be as satiric as you like. Viewing the world through a microscope is your prerogative.
这是艘战舰
This is a ship of war.
为了尽好职责  我什么都愿意做
I will grind whatever grist the mill requires to fulfill my duty.
甚至不惜一切?
Whatever the cost?
不惜一切
Whatever the cost.
盲目地服从命令
To follow orders with no regard for cost.
这难道不是意气用事吗?
Can you really claim there's nothing personal in this call to duty?
军人的天职就是服从命令
Orders are subject to the requirement of the service.
我奉命一定要追到巴西  我早就完成任务了
My orders were to follow him as far as Brazil. I exceeded my orders a long time ago.
我抓住了
Got it.
风向改变了
The wind's backing, sir.
我们不能继续向西航行
Sir, we just can't hold this westerly course any longer.
不能直走就绕过去  往南航行
If we can't sail through the damn wind, we'll bloody well sail around it. Due south.
多远?
How far south, sir?
要多远就多远
As far as is necessary, Mr Pullings.
-是  船长  -打起精神
-Aye, sir. -Lively.
-往南航行  波登  -是  往南
-Due south, please, Mr Bonden. -Due south, sir.
用力稳住
Heave. Steady.
很显然发生了很有趣的事  只是我完全不懂
Clearly something nautical and fascinating just happened. I am at a loss.
我们往北转向  我们又朝着太阳航行
We have made our turn northward. We are headed back toward the sun.
敬太阳
To the sun.
为了庆祝这件事
And by way of anticipation of this event,
我请基里克做了些好东西
I have asked Killick to prepare something special.
-基里克  好了没  -我早就好了
-Killick. Killick there. -I'm already here, ain't I?
各位  这就是...
Gentlemen, I give you,
我们的目的地
our destination.
-那是加拉巴哥群岛  -加拉巴哥群岛
-It's the Galapagos Islands. -The Galapagos Islands.
我们的捕鲸船队在那儿
Our whaling fleet is there.
它们的渔获量很值钱  拿破仑想抢来当战争经费
And their cargo would put a pretty penny into old Bones-aparte's invasion purse.
"地狱号" 一定在那儿  我敢打包票
That's where the Acheron will be. Sure as there's carts to horses.
普灵  别客气
So, Mr Pullings, if you'll permit me,
来一块艾贝玛小岛
a slice of Albemarle.
至于你医生  雷东达岩礁
And for you, Doctor, Redondo Rock.
太好了
Perfect.
"地狱号" 是我的
And the Acheron for me.
*经过大风和大浪*
Safe and sound at home again Let the waters roar, Jack
*安全重返旧家园*
Long we tossed on the rolling main Now we're safe ashore, Jack
*勿忘你的老战友*
Don't forget your old shipmates
*同仇敌忾并肩作战*
We have worked the selfsame gun Quarterdeck division
*你装弹药我开炮  打赢胜仗凯旋归*
Sponger I, and loader you Through the whole commission
*安全重返旧家园*
Long we tossed on the rolling main Now we're safe ashore, Jack
*勿忘你的老战友*
Don't forget your old shipmates
加拉巴哥群岛
拉斯安甘达斯
Las...
魔幻之岛  听说那儿充满了奇异生物
The Enchanted Isles. They're said to be full of strange and wonderful beasts.
我们到了就补充粮食和水
When we get there, we'll have to stop for food and water.
我答应你  我们至少要待几天...
I promise you, during that time...several days at least...
你可以尽情搜集昆虫样本
you can wander at will, collecting bugs and beetles to your heart's content.
你是第一个去那儿的自然学家
You'll be the first naturalist to set foot on the islands, I'll wager.
那就太好了
I would like that of all things.
-这是一种昆虫吗?  -对
-Is it an insect? -Yes.
看起来不像  好像一根树枝
Doesn't look like one. I mean, it looks like a stick.
这就是重点
Yes, that's the whole point.
它必须伪装才能存活
It's disguised itself in order to survive.
这只蜘蛛伪装成一只蚂蚁
There's a spider that's disguised itself as an ant.
这种昆虫必须伪装成花刺
And here's an insect that's taken on the shape of a thorn
才不会被鸟吃掉
to save itself from the birds.
上帝改变了它们?
Did God make them change?
上帝改变它们?  是  没错
Does God make them change? Yes, certainly.
但是它们自己会改变吗?
But do they also change themselves?
这问题才值得深思
Now that is a question, isn't it?
加拉巴哥岛到了
Sir, we've raised the Galapagos.
我来了
I'm coming.
-瞧  在岩石后面  -我看到了
-Look. Beyond the rock. -Yes, I see.
那是什么东西  海鸥吗?
What is it? Curious, eh? Some type of gull?
-丑得要命  -好恶心  全身都长满疣
-There's an ugly devil. -Disgusting. It's got warts all over it.
全都是丑八怪
Ugly devils, aren't they?
没有女人  只有鸭子跟蜥蜴
I can't see any women. Just ducks and lizards.
没有女人真是不自然
What, no women? It ain't natural.
太不可思议了
How extraordinary.
什么?
What is, sir?
那些鸟是某种鸬鹚  但是它们不能飞
Those birds. They're a species of cormorant, but they are flightless.
它们的翅膀退化了?
Do you see their underdeveloped wings?
这是新发现的物种
By all that's holy, I think that's unknown to science.
它们不怕那些恐龙
The dragons don't seem to bother them.
那是鬣鳞蜥  素食动物
They're a type of iguana, I should think. Therefore, they're vegetarian.
-你要抓一只吗?  -抓一对吧?
-Will you catch one? -A pair of them, I should think.
它们生下的后代  你可以送给国王
Then you can present one of their offspring to the king.
-有一只要游泳  -它们不会游泳
-Look. There's one going for a swim. -Iguanas don't swim.
这些就会游泳
These ones do.
我的天啊
I'll be damned.
才刚来就发现两个新物种  太惊人了
Two new species in as many minutes. That's remarkable.
各就各位  抛下缆索准备救人
All hands about ship. Off tacks and sheets. Prepare the mainsail to haul.
-我是奥布里船长  -我是信天翁号领航员霍格
-Aubrey. -Hogg. Master of the Albatross.
老天保佑你  老天保佑大家
God bless you, Captain. God bless you all.
-科勒米  给这些人食物和清水  -是
-Mr Calamy, food and water for these men. -Aye, sir.
-霍华德  解除戒备  -陆战队员  把枪放下
-Mr Howard, stand your men down. -Royal Marines, trail arms.
我们一星期前来补充装备时
We was coming back for fresh lines no more than a week ago.
遭到偷袭  狗娘养的海盗把我们的船烧掉
Hid in that inlet yonder. Burnt our bloody ship to the waterline. Fucking pirates.
船员被囚  船长遇害
Crew prisoner, captain dead.
一艘黑色三桅帆船  损失惨重
She were a big black three-master. Break your heart, it would.
一万两千英镑和上等鱼油  我们出海两年的收获
$12,000 sterling of the finest grade oil they took. We been out more than two years.
它的航向?
And her course?
西偏南11度  跟着捕鲸船队
Maybe a point south of west, following the rest of the fleet.
普灵  记下他们的名字
Mr Pullings, enter these men's names into the ship's books.
艾伦  航向西偏南
Mr Allen, set a course. West by south.
全体船员启航
All hands, make sail.
不补充粮食吗?
Sir, should we not take on fresh provisions?
一分一刻都不能浪费
Mr Mowett, there's not a moment to lose.
-你忘了你的承诺吗?  -我必须完成任务
-Have you forgotten your promise? -Subject to the requirements of the service.
不能为了抓髭鳞蜥延误时间
I cannot delay for the sake of an iguana or a giant peccary.
它们很有趣但是没有用
Fascinating, no doubt, but of no immediate application.
有个方法能让我们两全其美
There is, I think, an opportunity here to serve both our purposes.
这是座狭长小岛
As I understand it, this is a long, thin island.
你一定要绕过去才能出海  我可以走到小岛另一边
You need to sail around it. I could walk across it.
你光是看空鸟巢就会看半天
I have known you to spend hours staring into a deserted bird's nest.
我可以走快点  只做重要的测量
I could walk briskly, pausing only for important measurements.
这些是自然历史的重大发现
Making discoveries that could advance our knowledge of natural history.
如果风向允许我就会答应
If wind and tide had been against us, I should have said yes.
可惜没有  我必须说不
They're not. I'm obliged to say no.
我明白了  所以我只能委曲求全
I see. So after all this time in your service,
乖乖参加这场无谓的追逐战
I must simply content myself to form part of this belligerent expedition,
你错过自然的宝藏  只为摧毁敌人  权力让你完全腐化
hurry past wonders, bent on destruction. I say nothing of the corruption of power...
-别忘了你的身份  -不
-You forget yourself, Doctor. -No, Jack.
你才忘了自己是谁  做人一定要信守承诺
You've forgotten yourself. For my part, I look upon a promise as binding.
我的承诺有条件  这是艘战舰不是私人游艇
The promise was conditional. I command a king's ship, not a private yacht.
我们可没时间陪你玩
We do not have time for your damned hobbies, sir.
好吧
All right.
把鱼拿下去  冲洗甲板
Get those fish below. Sluice down this deck.
把他们带下去
Davies, don't leave them there. Get them below.
布雷克尼
Mr Blakeney.
我在甲板上找到一只怪虫
Sir, I found a curious beetle walking along the deck.
我猜是加拉巴哥甲虫
I think it's a Galapagos beetle.
一定是
I'm sure of it.
你在岛上走半天可能都找不到
Were you to walk all day on the island, you might never come across it.
没错  很有可能
Yes, that is more than likely sure.
你可以拿去
You can have it, sir.
布雷克尼
Mr Blakeney.
谢谢你
-Thank you. -Sir.
发射完毕
Last gun fired, sir.
-时间?  -两分零一秒
-Timing? -Two minutes and one second, sir.
各位  这太慢了  一定要比敌人快两倍
Lads, that's not good enough. We need to fire two broadsides to her one.
-你们想被法国佬打败吗?  -不想
-Want to see a guillotine in Piccadilly? -No.
-想让拿破仑当国王吗?  -不想
-Do you want to call Napoleon your king? -No.
-想让小孩唱法国国歌吗  -不想
-Want your children to sing The Marseillaise? -No.
准备到右舷开炮
Mr Mowett, Mr Pullings, starboard battery.
动作要快整齐划一
Jump to it, lads. Cadence and rhythm.
-瞄准目标  -快点
-Mark your targets. -Come on, lads, faster now.
上弹药
Come on, swab it.
哈伦跟上去
Heave.
-报告  -我们准备好了
-Report, Mr Mowett. -Third and fourth divisions ready.
好  右舷炮兵开炮
Right. Starboard battery, fire!
一分十秒
One minute and ten seconds.
干得好  大家都有酒喝
Well done, lads. Extra grog for all of you.
让给船长过
Gangway for the captain, lads.
进步很多  干得好
Marked improvement, Mr Calamy. Well done.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
基里克好了没  今晚吃什么?
Killick. Killick there. What do you have for us tonight?
酒酿猪脸肉
Which it's soused hog's face.
-酒酿猪脸肉  -我最爱吃的菜
-Which it is soused hog's face. -My favorite.
*我们要把它轰回姥姥家...*
And when they run, the Surprise will blow her to kingdom come.
再过一礼拜他们就会被渴死
One more week of this and they'd give it up for a cup of water.
我不会造雨
I can't make it rain.
我只能驭风  我不是万能的
I can harness the wind, but I ain't its goddamn creator.
我从来没碰过这种霉运
I have never known such a run of bad luck.
"众人问他  灾祸是谁造成的?"
"And they said unto him 'For what caused the evil?"'
他从哪儿蹦出这句话?
Where'd that come from?
圣经  旧约圣经  约拿书
It's from the Bible, that. That is from the Bible. The story of the Jonah.
他们在船上发现约拿...
They found out on their ship that one of their men...this Jonah cove...
他触怒上帝  带来霉运
he'd offended God and was the cause of all their bad luck.
邪恶来自心存邪念  做坏事的人
Evil comes from him who evil thinks and evil is.
不  乔的确对邪恶略知一二
No. Joe knows a thing or two about evil.
你有亲身经验对吧?
From personal experience. Right, Joe?
基里克说的没错
It's like Killick says.
那天早上他不敢击鼓备战
Morning of the battle, he doesn't have the guts to beat to quarters.
结果他的手下都挂了  他一爬上后桅  瓦利就落海了
Then his entire gun crew's killed. Soon as he went up the mizzen, Will falls.
换他值星  结果风就停了?
And whose watch was it when we lost our wind?
你站住
You there. Stand fast.
把他带下去  铐起来
Master-at-arms, take that man below and clap him in irons.
第八钟响时举行鞭刑
Mr Pullings, defaulters at eight bells.
遵命
Aye, sir.
把哈伦带到我的舱房
Bring Hollom down to my cabin.
你被他顶撞了怎么一句话也不说?
A man pushed past you, yet you said nothing. Why?
我想说  却说不出口
I intended to, sir, but the right words didn't...
说不出口?  他这是以下犯上
The right words? He was deliberately insubordinate.
我试着跟他们做朋友
I've tried to get to know the men, sir, and be friendly,
他们却故意整我
but they've taken a set against me.
老在我背后说我坏话  不停地给我白眼
Always whispering when I go past and giving me looks.
以后我会对他们凶一点
I'll set that to rights. I'll be much tougher on them.
你不能跟水手做朋友
You don't make friends with the foremastjacks, lad.
他们会看不起你
They'll despise you in the end, think you weak.
你也不必当暴君
-Nor do you need to be a tyrant. -No, sir.
是  对不起
I'm very sorry, sir.
-你26还是27岁?  -下礼拜就满30了
-You're 26? 27? -I'm 30 next Friday, sir.
30?
你两次考上尉都没过
You've failed to pass for lieutenant twice.
你表现不差  也有航海知识  你不能一辈子都当见习官
I know you have, but you're not a bad sailor. You can't spend your life a midshipman.
是的  我会更努力
No, sir. I will try much harder, sir.
听好  他们需要的是领导
Look, Hollom, it's leadership they want.
还有力量
Strength.
找出自身那种特质  就会得到他们的尊敬
You find that within yourself, and you will earn their respect.
没有尊敬哪来的纪律?
Without respect, true discipline goes by the board.
是的
Yes, sir.
力量  尊敬  还有纪律
Strength, respect and discipline, sir.
这是件很遗憾的事
It's an unfortunate business, Hollom.
实在遗憾
Damned unfortunate.
-下去吧  -是
-That'll be all. -Yes, sir.
-我也不喜欢鞭刑  -大家都认为是哈伦...
-I am not a flogging captain. -Hollom is a scapegoat for all the bad luck,
带来霉运
real or imagined, on this voyage.
请你过来
Mr Lamb? If you please.
他们都筋疲力尽
They're exhausted. These men are exhausted.
你把他们操练得太凶
You've pushed them too hard.
我是请你来跟我聊天
Stephen, I invite you to this cabin as my friend.
不是质疑我的命令
Not to criticize nor to comment on my command.
我是不是该等你气消了才来?
Shall I leave you until you're in a more harmonious frame of mind?
-你要我怎样?  -把船上的酒都倒掉
-What would you have me do? -Tip the ship's grog over the side.
-不给他们喝酒?  -纳格当时喝醉了
-Stop their grog? -Nagle was drunk when he insulted Hollom.
你要我取消两百年的传统
Stop 200 years of privilege and tradition.
他们有酒喝就不会叛变
I'd rather have them three sheets to the wind than face a mutiny.
我倒能理解他们会想叛变
I'm rather understanding of mutinies.
他们离乡背井  被困在监狱一般的船上...
Men pressed from their homes, confined for months aboard a wooden prison...
我很尊重你的意见  但是我不能承受船员叛变
I respect your right to disagree with me, but I can only afford one rebel on this ship
你看不起海军就是看不起我
I hate it when you talk of the service in this way. It makes me so very low.
你以为我想鞭打纳格吗?
You think I want to flog Nagle?
他跟我切断绳子  害他好友送死
A man who hacked the ropes that sent his mate to his death?
在我的命令下
Under my orders?
看到没  没有纪律  这艘船就会一团混乱
Do you not see? The only things that keep this wooden world together are hard work...
他只是没向长官敬礼
Jack, the man failed to salute.
连大自然都有阶级之分
There's hierarchies even in nature.
-大自然没有鄙视和羞辱  -不管他们是不行的
-There is no disdain in nature. There is no... -Men must be governed.
有时候管不好 但一定要管
Often not wisely, but governed nonetheless.
这是史上每个暴君的藉口 从尼禄到拿破仑都一样
That's the excuse of every tyrant in history, from Nero to Bonaparte.
我反对独裁专制 那只会带来痛苦与迫害
I, for one, am opposed to authority. It is an egg of misery and oppression.
你想搞革命来错地方了
You've come to the wrong shop for anarchy, brother.
四
Four.
五
Five.
六
Six.
七
Seven.
八
Eight.
九
Nine.
十
Ten.
十一
Eleven.
十二
Twelve.
把他放下来
Cut him down.
轻声一点
Not so loud.
把刀子放下来
Put that dirk down, Boyle.
你没事吧?
You OK, Mr Hollom?
-他没病  只是想偷懒  跟以前一样  -闭嘴
-He's not ill, just dodging work as usual. -Shut up.
-你闭嘴  -别管他
-You shut up. -Just leave him be.
-喝一点水  -谢谢你
-Have some water. -Thank you.
哈伦生病了
Sir, it's Mr Hollom.
他的身体没病  他认为自己受到诅咒
There's nothing physically wrong with him. He thinks he's been cursed.
水手什么都不怕  只怕碰到瘟神
Sailors can abide a great deal, but not a Jonah.
你怎么也信怪力乱神这一套
My God. You believe it too.
不是每件事都有科学根据的
Not everything is in your books, Stephen.
就是他对吧?
It's him, innit?
他是瘟神
The Jonah.
都是他害的
He's causing it.
鬼船是他召来的
He's callin' it up, don't you see?
每次他值星  那艘船就会出现
Every time he's on watch, that ship appears.
等着瞧吧
You wait and see.
今晚他值星  鬼船一定会出现
Anytime tonight, that ghost ship's gonna turn up.
它会把我们带到十八层地狱
And it's gonna take us all with it, straight down to the hot place.
哈伦
Mr Hollom.
你吓了我一大跳
You gave me such a start.
你好点了吗?
Are you feeling better now?
好多了  谢谢
Yes. Much better, thank you.
船长说明天就会起风
The captain thinks we'll get our wind tomorrow.
一定会的
I'm sure of it.
你一直都对我很好
You've always been very kind to me.
再见了  布雷克尼
Goodbye, Blakeney.
约拿书
事实是  不是所有人都能如愿以偿
The simple truth is, not all of us become the men we once hoped we might be.
但我们都是上帝的子民
But we are all God's creatures.
如果有人对哈伦有微词
If there are those among us who thought ill of Mr Hollom,
说过他坏话
or spoke ill of him,
或是瞧不起他这个人
or failed him in respect of fellowship,
我们乞求上帝的原谅
then we ask for your forgiveness, Lord.
还有他的原谅
And we ask for his.
赞美上帝
God be praised. Mr Mowett?
停在那儿
Avast there.
-有只鸟跟着我们  -什么鸟?
-Doctor, have you seen the bird? -What sort of bird?
有点像信天翁  要不然就是大个海鸥  它又来了
Some sort of albatross. Either that, or he's a prodigious great mew. There it goes.
那儿  它是我的
There he is. My bird. Damn.
它在兜圈子
It's circling, lads.
医生
Doctor?
天  医生
My God. Doctor.
对不起  那只鸟冲下来  我没看到你
I'm so sorry, man. The bird dropped low. I didn't see you.
-科勒米  快去叫希根  -我没事
-Calamy, get Higgins. -I'm fine, Jack.
子弹把一块布打进去了
The bullet took in a piece of shirt with it.
不取出来就会生脓溃烂
Unless it's removed, it's gonna suppurate and fester.
你行吗?
Are you equal to the task?
我先得看医生的书  研究一些图片
I'll need to read up on the doctor's books. Study some pictures he has.
研究图片?
Study some pictures?
先让我搞清状况
It's just to get my bearings, that's all.
在陆地上比较容易  不会摇摇晃晃
It'd be a lot easier if I were on dry land. You wouldn't have the...
我行的  等着瞧
I'll manage. You'll see.
海平线上有船帆  往西
Sail on the horizon, sir. Running west.
我们不确定  但应该就是它
We're not sure, but we think it's her, sir.
要去...
Better get...
再见了医生
Goodbye, sir.
就是那艘法国船
No mistakin' it. She's the Frenchie.
你要击鼓备战吗?
Shall we beat to quarters, sir?
跟我说  这是不是为了我
Tell me this wasn't on my account.
当然不是  我只想下来走走  伸伸腿
No, not at all. I just needed to stretch my legs.
轻点
Gently there.
快点  准备好
Briskly now. Secure this line.
每20码都有陆战队员驻守
Royal Marines posted every 20 yards, sir.
-准备好了吗?  -好了
-All set, Higgins? -Yes, sir.
不
No.
我要自己来
I do this with my own hand.
没事的话我就出去等
If everything is under control, I'll just be outside.
你的手很稳  我需要你
A spare pair of steady hands wouldn't go amiss.
除非你见到血就会昏倒
That is, if, of course, you have the constitution for this kind of thing.
亲爱的医生  我什么血腥的场面都见过了
My dear doctor, I have been amongst and around wounds all my life.
那就好
Good, then.
把手放在我肚子上  我会叫你用力按
Put your hand on my belly, pressing firmly when I give the word.
希根  手术刀
Higgins, the catling, if you please.
巴丁  镜子
Padeen, please.
探测器
The sounder, Mr Higgins.
擦血
Swab.
好
All right.
希根  你要帮我把肋骨撑开来
Mr Higgins, you'll have to raise the rib.
用力握住牵引器
Take a good grip with the square retractor.
插进去
Right in.
往上扳
And lift up.
往上
Lift up.
帮我擦血  我看不到
Swab, Jack. I can't see.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
夹到了
I got it.
按用力一点
A tad more pressure.
-全都在吗?  -对
-Is that all of it? -Aye, sir.
能完全缝回去
She'll patch up nicely.
谢天谢地
Thank God I got it.
很好喝
That's good.
-我跟巴丁替你采集样本?  -真的吗?
-Padeen and I have been collecting for you. -Have you really?
我连甲虫栖息的植物也带回来了
The beetles each come with a specimen of the plant they were found on.
那只逃走了
Padeen, that one's got away.
你要是愿意看的话  我做了一些笔记
Sir, I've made a few notes, if you want to see them.
布雷克尼  你有当自然学家的料
Mr Blakeney, it would appear that you have the makings of a naturalist.
我可以跟你一样文武双全
Perhaps I could combine them to be a sort of fighting naturalist, like you, sir.
战争和科学不太搭轧
They don't combine too well, I find.
好
Right.
你还不能起来吧?
Should you really be getting up, sir?
-你也是医生吗?  -不是
-Mr Blakeney, are you also a doctor? -No, sir.
没错  巴丁  扶我
No, you're not. Padeen, if you please.
你知道船长打算待多久吗?
How long does the captain intend that we stay? Do you know?
-一个礼拜吧  -一礼拜?
-Oh, a week perhaps. -A week?
-我并不急  -不是该去马克萨斯吗?
-There's no great hurry. -Mustn't we make haste for the Marquesas?
我都不确定那是不是 "地狱号"
I'm not even sure it was the Acheron we sighted.
就算是它也早就走远了
And if it was, she'll be well away by now.
要找到它是海底捞针
Like looking for an honest man in parliament.
趁英法和谈之前回家吧
No, we shall head home. Before peace breaks out with France, God forbid.
你这份恩情我恐怕无法报答
I fear you may have burdened me with a debt I can never repay.
用我的名字替灌木命名  全身带刺难以消灭的那种
Tosh. Name a shrub after me. Something prickly and hard to eradicate.
灌木?  才不要  我要用你的名字替大乌龟命名
A shrub? Nonsense. I'll name a great tortoise after you.
欧氏海龟
Testudo aubreii.
东西收一收  该走了
Come on, pack up your things. We should be going.
-回营地吗?  -不  到小岛另一端
-Back to camp, sir? -No, to the other side of the island.
-至少要走十英里路  -那就更一刻也不能耽搁
-But, sir, that must be at least ten miles. -Then there's not a moment to lose.
我在那儿看到过不会飞的鸬鹚
That's where I saw my flightless cormorant.
走吧
Come on.
长七英寸
Seven inches in length.
宽四英寸
Four inches wide.
颈长十五英寸
15-inches-long neck.
最宽处的宽度是六英寸
Width at the widest point, six inches.
可以用手抓它们  不会咬人
Padeen, put the net down and use your hands. They won't bite.
这只不错
Here's a good one.
小心抓
Pick them up carefully.
我们该回去了
Sir, I think we should be getting back.
在这儿军纪一点也没有用  我一定要找到鸬鹚
Naval discipline doesn't operate out here, Mr Blakeney. I must find that cormorant.
要是它真的不会飞
And should it indeed prove flightless,
你可以跟我并列名为发现者
you can join me at the Royal Society dinner as co-discoverer.
我们要快一点
Sir, we must hurry.
你来背他  放下来  别管了
Padeen, you must carry him. Put those down. Leave them. Just put everything down.
把笼子打开
Open the cages.
-快上船  各就各位  -方向舵向右
-All hands, unmoor ship. -Mr Allen, I'll have her on a starboard tack.
帮忙把乌龟放好
Let's have hands to stow these tortoises.
波登  方向舵向右
Barret Bonden, put your helm hard to starboard.
它往南航行了两个钟头
He has a head start of two hours on us and he's bearing south.
目的地一定是查理王岛  它在找清水
That can only mean King Charles Island. He's looking for water.
就算追得上去也无法偷袭它  除非我们能隐形
If we caught up with her, to take her, we'd have to be bloody invisible.
帆往右舷拉
Brace the yards to starboard.
史蒂芬  你发现那只鸟了吗?
So, Stephen, did you get to see your bird?
没有  不过...其实有啦  只是没办法抓到
No. Well, yes, but I couldn't catch one.
我最大的发现是那艘鬼船
My greatest discovery was your phantom.
没错  很遗憾你得把样本丢掉
Indeed it was. I'm sorry you had to leave the majority of your collection behind.
其实呢  我跟威尔有一样有趣的发现
In actual fact, Mr Blakeney and I did make one very interesting find.
是吗?
Is that right?
让我猜猜  这是一根树枝?
Let me guess. A stick?
告诉他
Tell him about it, Mr Blakeney.
-这是罕见的竹节虫  -竹节虫?
-It's a rare phasmid, sir. -A phasmid?
它为了躲避掠食者  可以伪装成树枝
It's an insect that disguises itself as a stick in order to confuse its predators.
"妖女号"
这也算是一种伪装
A nautical phasmid, Doctor.
对敌人来说这就是一艘捕鲸船
At least, to a hungry eye, if one has an appetite for whalers.
我打算从现在开始  多了解自然生物
I intend to take a greater interest in the bounty of nature from now on.
没想到研究自然生态也能有助于提高海上战略水平
I had no idea that a study of nature could advance the art of naval warfare.
我懂了
I see.
我要设下陷阱逮这个掠食者
Now to pull this predator in close and spring our trap.
-杰克?  -在
-Jack? -Yes.
你才是掠食者
You're the predator.
在那儿看不到船身
There. Hull-down, broad off the larboard bow.
就是它  没错
That's a frigate, all right.
你的眼力真好
Damn, you've got good eyes, Barret.
浓烟再多一点
-Mr Allen. More smoke. -Aye, sir.
这样就能把它引过来
That'll bring 'em about.
擦干净才会射得更直更准
That's it, lads. Clean 'em up so they fly straight and true.
打火石要放进去
Let's have fresh flints in all the locks.
把左舷大炮后轮卸下来
Larboard battery, unship your rear wheels.
放下来
Drop the gun.
-基里克  你也要换衣服  -天
-Come on, Killick, you too. Get dressed. -Oh, God.
-汤姆  -一切准备就绪
-Tom? -Our preparations are completed, sir.
很好  现在起  不准叫我长官  不准敬礼  不准鸣笛...
Good. Right, from now on no "sirs," no salutes, no whistles, no bells.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
...我们都不太习惯
Yes, I think we're all finding that quite difficult.
地狱号上关了30名捕鲸船员
There'll be 30 or more whalers locked in the Acheron's hold.
科勒米负责率人营救他们
After we board, Mr Calamy should take a party and free them.
-他行吗?  -当年你行吗?
-You think him ready, sir? -Were you ready, Tom?
-也许他能扭转战局  -没错
-He may well turn the tide. -Indeed, sir.
它上钩了  转向
She's taken the bait. Let's come about.
装成捕鲸船员  动作慌张
Make a show of fleeing, panicky and disorganized, like a whaler might.
除了霍格以外
Present company excepted, Mr Hogg.
各就各位  快点  别让他们看到
Hurry up, or they'll see you.
别管了  快上来扮成捕鲸船员
Eckhart, leave that. Just come up quick and get some whaler's slops on.
-恭喜了  彼得  你升了三副   -谢谢
-Congratulations. Acting third lieutenant. -Thank you.
-听说我们要去营救捕鲸船员  -你要在后甲板留守
-I hear we're to free the whalers. -You're to be stationed on the quarterdeck.
很遗憾
I'm sorry, Will.
我要你们把船开得歪七扭八  让它迎风追上来
Make a bad show of keeping your course. Let her run up and luff every now and then.
-对不起  -把帽子脱下来  我们是捕鲸人
-Excuse me, sir. -Remove your hat. We're whalers.
我想跟你谈谈  科勒米说我不能登船进攻...
Mr Calamy says I'm not on the boarding party. I want to say...
我知道你想说什么  我的答案是不行
I know what you want to say. And my answer is no.
你要率领你的炮兵  等我登上敌舰后指挥这艘船
You'll lead your gun crew, then when we board, you'll take command of the ship.
-你明白吗?  -你要我指挥这艘船?  谢谢
-Do I make myself clear? -Take command of the ship? Thank you, sir.
-回到岗位上  -是
-Back to your station. -Yes, sir.
绑在右手辨别敌我
On your right upper arm, to tell friend from foe.
绑在这只手  你的右手
Davies, this arm. Starboard arm.
-是你断的那只手吗?  -说话小心点
-Is that the arm you got or don't got? -Less of that cheek, Davies.
把领巾绑在右臂
Take your neck cloths and put them round your right upper arm.
船长来了
Make way for the captain.
恭喜了  三副
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
很好  伙伴们
Right, lads.
我知道你们都很英勇
I know there's not a faint heart among you,
你们跟我一样很想杀敌报国
and I know you're as anxious as I am to get into close action.
但是我们要先把他们引过来
But we must bring him right up beside us before we spring this trap.
这要考验我们的胆识
That will test our nerve.
还有纪律  跟勇气一样重要
And discipline will count just as much as courage.
地狱号不好对付  大炮和船员比我们多两倍
The Acheron is a tough nut to crack. More than twice our guns and numbers.
他们会顽强抵抗
And they will sell their lives dearly.
掌帆员  你们要先装得笨手笨脚
Topmen, your handling of the sheets to be lubberly and un-navylike,
等我下令就把帆一收
until the signal to spill the wind from our sails.
我们就会停下来
This will bring us almost to a complete stop.
炮兵要迅速把大炮推出炮门
Gun crews, you must run out and tie down in double-quick time.
没有后轮能射得更高
With the rear wheels removed you've gained elevation,
但是却不能重新装弹药
but without recoil you can't reload.
所以左舷大炮只能开一次炮  记着  只能开一次
So, gun captains, that gives you one shot from the larboard battery. One shot only.
瞄准主桅射击  一定要把它击倒
You'll fire for her mainmast. Much will depend on your accuracy.
它就算动不了也很危险  就像受伤的野兽
However, even crippled she will still be dangerous, like a wounded beast.
霍华德队长率领你的陆战队员...
Captain Howard and the marines
要用回旋炮跟毛瑟枪  攻击对方的露天甲板
will sweep their weather deck with swivel gun and musket fire from the tops.
先替我们解决一些敌人
They'll try and even the odds for us before we board.
他们把这艘船当成大肥羊
They mean to take us as a prize.
这艘船如果没有损坏会比较值钱  他们的贪心会害他们送命
And we are worth more to them undamaged. Their greed will be their downfall.
祖国受到入侵者威胁
England is under threat of invasion.
这艘船就是我们的家园
And though we be on the far side of the world, this ship is our home.
这艘船就是祖国
This ship is England.
大家都要坚守岗位  以迅雷不及掩耳之速进攻
So it's every hand to his rope or gun. Quick's the word and sharp's the action.
杀他个措手不及屁滚尿流
After all, surprise is on our side.
丢高一点  让他们看到
-Toss them high so they can see them. -Hello, Doctor.
杰克
Jack.
-抽根雪茄  -不了谢谢
-Care for a cigar? -Thank you, no.
这是你的
If you please, Doctor.
-我替你叫了咖啡  -谢谢
-I took the liberty, Doctor. -Thank you, Killick.
-我加了三块方糖  -你真好心
-There's three lumps in there. -How kind.
-祝好运  威尔  -好运
-Good luck, Will. -Good luck, Peter.
-待会见  -好
-See you afterwards. -And you.
稳住  保持冷静
Steady now, lads. Keep calm.
"妖女号" 捕鲸船  这是地狱号
English whaler Syren, this is Acheron.
你们已经无处可逃  这算是警告
You have no possibility, no chance. But you have had warning.
不停船就把你们炸毁
Stop now, or we will destroy your ship.
英国捕鲸船  这是最后的警告
English whaler, this is your last warning.
不停船就把你们炸毁
Stop now, or we will destroy you.
大家上
Let fly!
拖过去
Haul your yards there.
快点
Run out, boys.
开炮
Fire!
瞄准主桅
For the mainmast, lads.
-让我过去  -开炮
-Let me through. -Fire!
向左急转
Hard a-larboard.
张起前桅帆和中桅帆
Right the headsails. Set the topsails.
升起来
Heave.
快到右舷
Man the starboard battery.
看到目标就开炮
Fire as she bears.
接近
Get to it.
被主桅挡住  过不去
It's the fallen mast. We can't lay alongside.
划小艇试着过去  我会尽量掩护你们
Cross the wreckage as best you can. I'll draw their fire.
-跟普灵一起去  -收起中桅帆
-My division to join Mr Pullings. -Clew up topsails.
幸运杰克万岁
Huzzah for Lucky Jack.
抛出勾绳
Grappling hooks away.
放下登船跳板
Run out the boarding planks.
-跟我来  -为了祖国和这只大肥羊
-My division, follow me. -For England, for home, and for the prize.
冲啊
Here we go, lads.
别出声  安静
Pipe down. Silence.
看来他们全军覆没
Looks like the job is done, sir.
地狱号
Acheron.
开火
Fire!
布雷克尼  快开炮
Mr Blakeney, the nine-pounder.
来吧
That's it.
开炮
Fire!
继续前进  前进
Keep moving, men. Keep moving.
乔
Joe.
丢炸弹
Grenades, ready.
他们瞄准了我们
They're aiming for our hull.
想把我们炸沉  炮管朝下
They could sink us. Depress the muzzle.
把后面抬起来
Padeen, train it aft.
消灭敌人
Together now.
让开
Stand clear.
开炮
Fire!
拿武器攻过去
Arm yourselves. We must board them.
跟我来
Follow me.
上啊
Now.
捕鲸船员  跟我来  快点跟上来
Whalers, follow me. Mr Hogg, down below. Quickly now.
信天翁号船员  听到吗?
Albatrosses. Albatrosses, do you hear me?
快阻止他们
To the guns.
把火药浇熄
Boyle, douse that gun's priming.
快点  快走
Lively there. Come on. Move.
英勇杀敌吧
Now do your worst.
霍华德
-Mr Howard. -Sir.
-他们降旗了吗?  -降了
-Have they struck their colors? -I believe so.
-找到船长了吗?  -还没有
-Has their captain been sighted? -Not yet, sir.
继续吧
-Carry on. -Aye, sir.
我是狄医生
Docteur de Vigny, monsieur.
我已经尽力了
I did what I could for him.
船长死前要我把这把剑交给你
Before the capitaine died, he said I was to give you this.
不  让我来
No. I'll do it.
请你帮忙
Can you help me?
我们在天上的父
Our Father,
愿人都尊你的名为圣
who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
愿你的国降临  愿你的旨意行在地上
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
如同行在天上
on earth as it is in heaven.
赐给我们日用的饮食
Give us this day our daily bread,
免我们的债  如同我们免了人的债
and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us.
不叫我们遇见试探  救我们脱离凶恶
And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
因为国度
For thine is the kingdom,
权柄  荣耀
the power and the glory,
全是你的  直到永远
forever and ever.
阿门
Amen.
罗伯特・加德纳  一等水兵
Robert Gardner, able seaman.
詹姆斯・劳埃德  水手长助手
James Lloyd, boatswain's mate.
罗伯特・坎普  一等水兵
Robert Kemp, able seaman.
约翰・安东尼奥  军需官助手
John Antonio, quartermaster's mate.
迈克尔・杜德  一等水兵
Michael Doudle, able seaman.
约瑟夫・纳格勒  木工助手
Joseph Nagle, carpenter's mate.
约翰・艾伦  领航员
John Allen, sailing master.
彼得・迈尔斯・科勒米
Peter Miles Calamy,
三副
lieutenant.
我们将他们的遗体抛入大海
We therefore commit their bodies to the deep,
让他们腐朽
to be turned into corruption,
等待大海让他们死而复生
looking for the resurrection of the body when the sea shall give up her dead,
在天国得到永生
and the life of the world to come,
以主耶稣基督之名
through our Lord Jesus Christ.
阿门
Amen.
我们的老朋友
It's our old friend.
把油漆传过来
Pass down a barrel of paint, please.
捕鲸船员和陆战队员都上船了
Sir, the whalers are all aboard and that's the last detachment of marines.
很好
Good.
我要回加拉巴哥岛
I think I shall return to the Galapagos.
补充粮水  让医生找他的鸟
Take on food and water and give the doctor a few days to find his bird.
好的
Very good, sir.
你要带地狱号到瓦尔帕莱索港
You, however, shall take the Acheron south to Valparaiso.
卸下人犯后到朴茨茅斯会合
Parole the prisoners there, refit as necessary, and we shall rendezvous in Portsmouth.
霍格将会是很好的领航员
I believe Mr Hogg would be a good choice for sailing master.
我让你自己决定  普灵船长
However, that will be your decision, Captain Pullings.
这是你的指令
Your orders.
-谢谢你  -祝你一帆风顺
-Thank you, sir. -Godspeed, Tom.
你也一样
And to you, sir.
-莫维?  -我的荣幸
-Mr Mowett? -With pleasure, sir.
-祝好运  -朴茨茅斯见
-Good luck. -See you in Portsmouth.
为普灵船长欢呼
Now, lads, huzzah for Captain Pullings.
-祝你好运  -祝好运  船长
-Good luck, sir. -Good luck, Captain.
他们又来了
Here we go again.
基里克  好了吗
Killick. Killick there.
好了我就会叫你
Which it will be ready when it's ready.
等他们靠岸我才放心
I'll rest easier when I know they've reached shore.
这么多伤患  只有可怜的希根照顾
So many wounded, and only that poor unfortunate Higgins to tend to them.
不过总比没医生来得好
Still, he's better than no doctor at all.
-我见过地狱号的医生  -他几个月前就发烧死了
-I met their doctor. I spoke to him. -No, he died of fever months ago.
狄医生吗?
De Vigny?
-我要见莫维  -莫维请到船长室
-Pass the word for Mr Mowett. -Mr Mowett to the great cabin.
这是他们的 "医生" 给我的
Their "doctor" gave me this sword.
改变航向  东南偏东
Mr Mowett, change of course. Southeast by east.
我们拦截地狱号  并把它护送到瓦尔帕莱索
We'll intercept the Acheron and escort them into Valparaiso.
遵命  东南偏东
Aye, sir. Sou'east by east.
威廉
-And William. -Sir?
-击鼓备战  -好的
-Beat to quarters. -Very good, sir.
你必须完成任务对吧
Subject to the requirements of the service.
史蒂芬  那只鸟不会飞吧?
Well, Stephen, the bird's flightless?
没错
Yes.
它哪儿也不会去的
It's not going anywhere.